

PROFILE

I am an energetic and ambitious person with an immense amount of travel & tourism knowledge, and customer service on top of my priorities. I also believe it is important to be flexible and adaptable in order to succeed in one's career.

Deciding to start my own travel business in February 2020 wasn't great timing but that doesn't mean I am unhappy that I tried. 2020/21 has been a year of learning and developing myself.

My previous role included managing a team of 5, working closely with the individuals to bring the team from a negative £25k to over £300k profit within a year, to which we received a platinum award in 2019.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+44 771 084 1607

FMAII:

tyrone.h.francis@gmail.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

DATE OF BIRTH: 13 August 1985

AGE: 35

NATIONALITY: South African / German

MARITAL STATUS: Single HEALTH: Excellence LANGUAGE: English

HOBBIES

Cooking, Olympic Weightlifting, Running, Cycling, Music and Travelling

CURRICULUM VITAE OF TYRONE FRANCIS

EDUCATION

The Hill Collage, Port Elizbeth, South Africa

Matriculated 2004

Subjects: English, Afrikaans, Hotel & Catering, Travel and Tourism, Computer Typing and Computer Studies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Self-employed – Trading under the name of Travel Counsellors Travel Manager

March 2020 - Current

Duties include but are not limited to:

- Making and managing GDS bookings; air, hotels, car hire, ticketing, time changes, date changes, re-routes.
- Finding new leads to gain more business
- Promoting my business through social media channels
- Ensuring customer retention and loyalty
- Planning my week including updating myself on new products & training sessions.
- Daily operational duties (Admin)
- Ensuring clients' pay their account in the required time frame

Corporate Traveller (Flight Centre Travel Group UK) Business Travel Consultant / Assistant Manager / Team Manager August 2015 to February 2020

I joined the Flight Centre Group for the second time in my travel career journey as a Business Travel Consultant, working my way up to run my own team of business travel consultants. Many duties were the same as my current self-employed roles, expect that I was managing a team which included a home worker who job shared, conducting monthly 1 to 1's and ensuring team development.

Travelstart, Online Travel Agent, South Africa Sales Consultant March 2013 – May 2015

Duties included but not limited to selling and booking: Flights, cruise, rail, car hire, accommodation, ski, travel insurance, and holiday packages in a call center environment. I also have experience in issuing and re-issuing flights, making group bookings from time to time, working with operators, airlines and customers, building up relationships to ensure the success of bookings, customer satisfaction and retention.

Flight Centre (Flight Centre Travel Group South Africa) Sales Consultant

December 2010 – February 2013

Duties included but not limited to selling and booking: Flights, cruise, rail, car hire, accommodation, ski, travel insurance, and holiday packages. Calculating re-issue, building up relationships with customers and suppliers to ensure the success of bookings, customer satisfaction and retention.

Princess Cruise Lines
Junior Assistant Purser
November 2008 – October 2010

There were many roles one did as Junior Assistant Purser. This included Passenger Service, Art Auction Assistant, Assistant Night Manager and Assistant Administration Officer.

ACHIEVEMENTS

2004 – Head boy

2015 – Moved to the United Kingdom

2020 – Advanced Nutrition and Dieting course

COMPUTER SYSTEMS

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel and Power Point) GDS (Global Distribution System): Amadeus and Galileo -For airline, hotels and car hire